<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>SEG/FAULT</title>
<link>https://h5law.com</link>
<description>A series of philosophical writings</description>
<atom:link href="https://h5law.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<item>
<title>Happiness</title>
<link>https://h5law.com/happiness.md</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 21:11:24 GMT</pubDate>
<description>Exploring a philosophic topic based on the title 'Happiness'</description>
<content>
I used to think happiness was something you reached. A moment where things
finally made sense, where effort softened into ease. But the longer I sit with
the question-*what is happiness?*-the less convincing that idea becomes.
Happiness, if it exists at all, does not seem to wait at the end of the road.
It walks beside us, often disguised as struggle.

The happiness we think of is often elusive; we can grasp it for a, or moments,
but it is gone just as quick as we got ahold of it. We are in an eternal
struggle to catch the next fix of happiness allotted to us. This struggle for
happiness is in our human nature, we crave it - long for it. But is it anything

more than an intense battle with struggle. A struggle with no permenant end.

In the meantime, of searching for happiness we suffer, we struggle, we are in
pain - the opposite of happiness, but without these feelings, there could be no

such thing as happiness. If we had never felt sad, pain, sorrow, we couldn't
even comprehend what happiness is in the slightest. But because we do there is
a chance for us. A chance for happiness.

But perhaps this happiness that we all chase is really a culmination of the pai
n
that brought us there. A respite of sorts, the pain, sorrow, etc. doesn't just
disappear but instead is masked by something more tolerable, something we put u
p
with even in the face of our immense weight we carry.

Happiness itself is absurd in essence, it's just an emotion but one with so muc
h
meaning. Why do we suffer for its sake, why go through pain for it too?

Life offers no clear instructions. There is no visible blueprint explaining why

we suffer, fail, or lose what we love. We want meaning, but the world does not
answer in language we can understand. And yet, despite this silence, we
continue. We wake up, we try again, we carry our weight uphill even when it
rolls back down.

What strikes me is that happiness doesn’t disappear in this confrontation—i
t
changes shape.

There is a kind of happiness that comes from resistance. Not the loud,
celebratory kind, but the quiet satisfaction of standing upright in a world
that does not bend for us. To keep going without illusions, without guarantees,

requires a certain inner strength. And in that strength, there is something
deeply alive.

Pain, too, plays an uncomfortable role. We are taught to avoid it, to see it as

proof that something has gone wrong. But pain often marks the moments when we
are most engaged with life—when we are growing, risking, choosing. A life
without friction might be comfortable, but it would also be shallow. Happiness
cannot be reduced to comfort without losing something essential.

I’ve come to think that happiness is less about what happens to us and more
about how we respond. Do we shrink from difficulty, or do we let it shape us? D
o
we resent the weight we carry, or do we claim it as ours? There is a subtle joy

in realizing that even when circumstances are unfair or absurd, our response
still belongs to us.

This doesn’t mean forcing optimism onto a broken situation. It means clarity.

Seeing the world as it is, stripped of false promises, and choosing to live
anyway. There is dignity in that choice. Even beauty.

Perhaps happiness is not the feeling that life is easy, but the realization tha
t
life is *worth engaging with*—even when it hurts, even when it makes no sense
.
It is found in effort, in persistence, in saying “yes” to existence without

demanding that it justify itself first.

So when I ask myself what happiness is, I no longer imagine a final state of
peace. I imagine movement. Struggle. Awareness. The steady act of living
honestly.

And maybe that is enough.

---
</content>
<guid>https://h5law.com/happiness.md</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Loneliness</title>
<link>https://h5law.com/loneliness.md</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 14:21:43 GMT</pubDate>
<description>Exploring a philosophic topic based on the title 'Loneliness'</description>
<content>
Loneliness is like a dagger in the side yet can be a blessing at the same time.

We can know the place they live intimately, and its inhabitants - even passing
a nod as they pass. But deep down they are still alone. This loneliness is like

a poison that eats from inside out and devours the spirit of the lonely. People

are social creatures and without that connection we are but empty shells walkin
g
around, lost, trapped in a potential prison of our own mind.

Yet, within that ache, solitude sharpens perception. In the quiet, the mind
learns its own contours; thoughts grow clearer, truer, unfiltered by the noise
of others. Loneliness teaches self-reliance and honesty, forcing one to confron
t
who they are when no one is watching. It can be a mirror as much as a wound.

Even with the mind knowing itself completely, there is nothing like a human
connection. To be held by someone, laugh with another, talk to yet another.
Being alone robs us of these natural gifts meant for humans, they isolate us
and give us a deadening melancholy. This melancholy continues to percolate
within us and eats all aspect of social interaction we may have until we are
inept in all social situations.

The danger lies not in being alone, but in believing one is unseen forever. Whe
n
solitude hardens into isolation, the poison takes hold. But when it is held
gently-acknowledged, not feared-it can become a threshold rather than a prison.

From that stillness, connection regains its meaning, and when another soul
finally meets yours, even briefly, it feels less like chance and more like
grace.

The connection with another can free us from all these evils previously
mentioned. It can be a relationship, friendship or a friendly acquaintance you
play with regularly. But the importance is connection. It frees us, and gives
us a chance at a life not alone and isn't this what grace is?

Just as the ache of loneliness and solitude can sharpen us as help us get to
know our real selves. So too can a true connection. It also can act as a mirror

and expose the real versions of ourselves the ones outside of our heads. We get

to know the person outside the mask we have built and the walls we have hid
behind. A true connection can destroy those walls and remove that mask and help

us see who we really are. They can help us even evolve who we are into someone
new, someone not alone, someone confident and friendly, someone we always
wanted to be.

---
</content>
<guid>https://h5law.com/loneliness.md</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Lost</title>
<link>https://h5law.com/lost.md</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:29:45 GMT</pubDate>
<description>Exploring a philosophic topic based on the title 'Lost'</description>
<content>
I wander through the quiet corridors of my mind, haunted by an absence that
echoes like a forgotten melody. It's as if I've lost something profound-a
whisper of potential, a shadow of what could have been-that I never truly
possessed. I never cradled it in my arms, never gazed upon its form under the
sun's indifferent light, never felt its weight pressing against my skin. And
yet, this elusive phantom has been my constant companion, woven into the fabric

of my days like an invisible thread, pulling at the edges of my existence.

How to live, then, in the wake of this paradoxical grief? To mourn what was
never mine feels like chasing ghosts in the fog-futile, yet inescapably human.
Perhaps the key lies in embracing the void, in recognizing that this "loss" is
the spark of longing that drives us forward. It teaches me to savor the tangibl
e
joys, to build from the ashes of unfulfilled dreams, and to find solace in the
rhythm of breath and heartbeat. For in acknowledging what I never had, I uncove
r
the richness of what I do - a life unfolding, imperfect and alive.

---
</content>
<guid>https://h5law.com/lost.md</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Purpose</title>
<link>https://h5law.com/purpose.md</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 04:13:52 GMT</pubDate>
<description>Exploring a philosophic topic based on the title 'Purpose'</description>
<content>
Purpose is an elusive thing. Some wake up full of vigor ready for the day ahead

with clear goals and intentions, with purpose. Others, however, wake up and lie

in bed all day, unmotivated and wish for their own deaths. I believe this to be

a problem with many things but one of them being purpose.

Purpose may not be what it is that drives people to get on with their lives,
or a lack thereof, take them. What is really at fault is an inability to see
the person in respect's future. If you cannot see yourself having a future,
whether it be the one you dreamed of, the one you envisiged or one at all. Then

you are at the mercy of "purpose".

Purpose, then, is not a starting point but a consequence. We often treat it as
something one must *discover*, as if it were buried beneath the surface of the
self, waiting to be unearthed. But perhaps purpose is not found at all-perhaps
it is *projected*. It emerges only when a person can imagine themselves
continuing, becoming, changing. When that imagined future collapses, purpose
does not vanish because it was never there to begin with; it simply never had
the chance to form.

This places us closer to the existentialists than we might be comfortable
admitting. If the future self is blurred or absent, the present self begins to
feel unreal, weightless. Days lose their narrative thread. Without a story that

extends forward, actions feel arbitrary, and effort seems unjustifiable. It is
not that life lacks meaning, but that meaning requires time to unfold-and time
requires belief in tomorrow.

Ironically, this suggests that purpose is not what saves us from despair;
rather, it is hope, however fragile or undefined. Not hope in a specific
outcome or dream, but hope in continuation itself. To believe that there will b
e
a “later” version of oneself-one capable of understanding, forgiving, or
reinterpreting the present-is to loosen the grip of purpose over one’s worth.
 In
this sense, purpose becomes less of a demand and more of a byproduct of
endurance.

Perhaps the task, then, is not to ask *“What is my purpose?”* but *“Can I

imagine myself still here?”* If the answer is even faintly yes, purpose may
follow on its own, quietly and without ceremony. And if it does not, that may b
e
acceptable too. After all, to exist without a clear purpose is not a failure of

life-it may simply be life before it has finished explaining itself.

---
</content>
<guid>https://h5law.com/purpose.md</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Absurd</title>
<link>https://h5law.com/absurd.md</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 16:45:38 GMT</pubDate>
<description>Exploring a philosophic topic based on the title 'Absurd'</description>
<content>
**‘Of a thing: against or without reason or propriety; incongruous, unreasona
ble, illogical’.**
We all have causes which seem absurd; whether they be belief in the unknown;
trust in what cannot be seen; irrational fears; unreasonable and illogical idea
s
and conceptions as well as a fear of the unknown. I put the latter in as we are

naturally inclined to fear what we don't know or understand. This fear although

completely real when felt is utterly absurd.

Absurdity, then, is not merely a flaw in logic or a failure of reason; it is a
fundamental condition of human experience. We are creatures who seek meaning in

a world that offers no clear answers, who demand coherence from systems that
resist it, and who construct elaborate explanations to soothe an unease we
rarely admit to ourselves. The absurd arises precisely at this intersection:
between our hunger for certainty and the universe’s indifference to it.

Much of what we call “belief” exists not because it is reasonable, but beca
use
it is comforting. Faith in unseen forces, destinies, or hidden orders often
fills the gaps left by uncertainty. These beliefs are not inherently foolish,
yet they rest on foundations that logic cannot fully support. We trust what
cannot be proven, hope in outcomes we cannot predict, and cling to narratives
that grant us a sense of control. In this way, absurdity becomes a coping
mechanism - a way of making the unbearable tolerable.

Fear plays an equally powerful role. The unknown terrifies us not because it is

dangerous by nature, but because it resists classification. We fear what we
cannot name, measure, or anticipate. Darkness is frightening not for what it
contains, but for what it conceals. This fear is instinctive and deeply rooted,

and yet, when examined, it collapses under scrutiny. The emotion is genuine, bu
t
its cause is often imagined. Here lies the paradox: our feelings are real, but
the logic behind them is not.

Human thought is riddled with contradictions of this kind. We pride ourselves o
n
rationality while acting irrationally. We value reason yet allow emotion to
dictate decisions. We reject illogical arguments while defending illogical
positions of our own. The absurd does not exist outside us - it thrives within
us. It is present in the superstitions we mock but secretly observe, the risks
we fear disproportionately, and the explanations we invent when truth is too
unsettling.

Philosophically, the absurd has often been framed as a conflict between meaning

and meaninglessness. We ask questions - Why are we here? What is the purpose of

this? - and receive no definitive response. The silence that follows is
unsettling.To live with it requires either acceptance or rebellion. Some choose

to imposemeaning where none is evident; others embrace the lack of it. Both
responses are,in their own way, absurd. Yet they are also deeply human.

Perhaps the true absurdity lies not in our fears or beliefs, but in our refusal

to acknowledge them as such. We spend considerable effort disguising our
uncertainties, presenting confidence where there is doubt and logic where
there is none. To admit absurdity feels like weakness, yet it may be the most
honest position available to us. Accepting that much of life is unreasonable
frees us from the exhausting pursuit of perfect sense.

In the end, absurdity is unavoidable. It is woven into our thinking, our
emotions, and our attempts to understand a world that does not owe us clarity.
Rather than something to be eradicated, it may be something to be recognized—
and
even embraced. For in acknowledging the absurd, we confront the limits of reaso
n
and, paradoxically, come closer to understanding ourselves.
</content>
<guid>https://h5law.com/absurd.md</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
